Never forget why you are the church.
Um, tonight, uh, we're going to be a
little bit of everywhere.
Um, if you if you want to,
You can go ahead and turn your Bibles to 2nd Thessalonians.
2nd Thessalonians.
I'm going to be completely transparent and honest.
Um, I have my
study time has been absolutely attacked this week.
And so, um, I am.
The good thing is, is I have resources that I can kind of
tap into and they're good resources.
And so I found a outline that I really appreciated for this time
because I was thinking, of all the things going on in my family
personally right now, and just, um, how I could challenge
and motivate and encourage not just you, but also myself
to keep on keeping on, even when it is difficult.
And so, uh, what we have here in 2nd Thessalonians
chapter one, um, I'm going to go ahead and read
it and then we'll get, uh, we'll get going on the night.
If you're there, say read.
We're going to read all of chapter one if you don't mind.
It says, Paul, and Savanus, and Timothy, unto
the church of the Thessalians, Thessalonians, and
God, our Father, and the Lord Jesus Christ, grace unto
you in peace from God, our Father, and the Lord Jesus Christ.
We were bound to thank God always for you, brethren, as it is
meat because that your faith groweth exceedingly in
the charity of every one of you all toward each other aboundeth,
so that we ourselves glory in you in the churches of God for
your patience and faith and all your persecutions
and tribulations that ye endure, which is
a manifest token of the righteous judgment of God, that ye may be counted
worthy of the kingdom of God for which ye also suffer.
Seeing it is a righteous thing with God to recompense tribulation
of them that trouble you, and to you who are troubled to
rest with us, when the Lord Jesus shall
be revealed from heaven, with his mighty angels,
inflaming fire, taking vengeance on them that know not God, and
that obey not the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ, who shall be punished,
with everlasting destruction, from the presence
of the Lord, and from the glory of his power, when he shall come to
be glorified in his saints,
and to be admired in all them that believe, because our testimony among
you is believed in that day.
Wherefore also we pray always for you, that
our God would account you worthy of this calling and fulfill
all the good pleasure of his goodness and the work of
faith with power, that the name of our Lord Jesus Christ might
be glorified, may be glorified in you, and ye in
him, according to the grace of our God, and the Lord,
Jesus Christ. tonight.
lets pray.
Father, I thank you for this night.
thank you for your word.
And even though I don't know what to say or what to do, God, Lord,
you direct and you God, and you point to the right direction, God.
And we thank you for that.
So God, I pray those that have ears, here may they hear.
And listen, Jesus ain't pray.
Amen.
Uh, tonight, has anyone ever heard of her?
I know Mike and Robin has, so you don't get to answer this one like little teacher pet things.
Like, I know you know the answer.
Anyone ever been a part of or done anything like a rehearsal?
Okay, rehearsals are important.
Why are rehearsal is important?
Somebody answered.
This is kind of...
Okay, practice, get it right, preparation,
right?
can look a lot of things.
Obviously, rehearsal for music, rehearsal for
a...
I mean, you could even rehearse for a speech you're going to give or whatever, rehearse
for what you do, right?
making sure you know where to go.
That's kind of what our security teams will be doing, making sure that we know what we're going to do.
We rehearse certain things so we can be prepared and
get it right when we need to.
I will tell you most of the time in my experience,
and most of my rehearsal experience has been basically with music, right?
For example, we're rehearsing tomorrow for
Sunday night, the worship night now, Alexandria.
We're going to get there early on Saturday to rehearse for the
student evangelism conference for that night.
What I'm trying to say is typically rehearsal is a lot more
difficult than the actual thing.
Why?
Because you're hashing things out, right?
You're trying to get it right.
You're making sure that everything's cohesive.
You're making sure that everything's prepared, everything's together, everything's flowing like it should.
Right?
And that takes time, that takes commitment.
Let me tell you something, when you don't rehearse, a lot of times things can go wrong, you know what I'm saying?
And so you say, why are we talking about rehearsals in this?
Well, life in general is full of rehearsals.
Let's think about that for a second.
Our business as a church is to teach people the word of God, aiding
them and living victoriously, therefore preparing
for the place called heaven.
Guys, listen, a lot of people, we say, well, I just one
day I hope to go to heaven.
Listen, we're rehearsing for heaven right now.
We are preparing for heaven right here, right now.
What we're doing together, gathered us.
What is going to be heaven?
The saints gathered for the glory of Christ.
What is the church right now?
Listen, we are rehearsing for what is to come.
We're rehearsing for heaven.
We are rehearsing for eternity.
The subject that we see tonight, rehearsal for heaven,
it brings to mind 3 challenges.
Again, I told you, a lot of times rehearsal is
a lot more challenging than the actual thing.
When we on Saturday night, when we lead that worship, right?
I mean, and the Holy Spirit can get involved in rehearsal.
He needs to be involved in rehearsal.
Amen?
Like if he's not, trust me, it's not fun.
But what I'm trying to say is, man, when we actually
get to going and we're leading those students in worship
that night, it's just going to flow out of us.
The Holy Spirit's just going to use that.
But it took preparation.
When we get to heaven, listen, why would we think that we're going to get to
heaven and start doing something that we've never done here?
Think about it for a second.
I can't wait to get to heaven, but man, I'm just not big on corporate worship.
That's what heaven is.
You understand that?
We're going to be corporately worshiping Christ for eternity.
Well, I just can't wait to get to heaven, but man, I'm not going to help a nursery.
Listen, you're going to be serving Christ in heaven.
In a 1000 year reign, ruling and reigning with Christ,
we're going to have a job, I believe, that God gives us to fulfill.
We're not going to be sitting on the couch watching church on TV in heaven.
We're gonna have a job.
We're going to have a purpose.
We're going to have a voice to worship him.
Are y'all with me tonight?
You understand what I'm saying?
So might as well rehearse right now.
Those 3 challenges and we're going to go through them very quickly.
We're going to be all over scripture.
The main the main verse here, I'm going to read in the NSB 95,
because it's a little bit easier to understand, but the main verse we
see in the KJV, it says, and to you who are troubled rest with us,
We just sang about that.
If you're troubled if you're weary, man, that hit me tonight.
And to you who are troubled, rest with us when the Lord Jesus shall be revealed
in heaven with his mighty angels.
I like how it says here, it says, and to give us relief to you who
are afflicted, and to us as well when the
Lord Jesus will be revealed from heaven with
his mighty angels and flaming fire.
Can I tell you something before I even get anywhere else?
When we talk about these challenges,
They're called challenges for a reason.
They're challenging.
But I want you to know something.
Jesus will return.
We are rehearsing for heaven that we will go to because of Christ.
So the 1st one we see this, we see the challenge of living for Christ.
See, there's a bunch of things that living for Christ means.
A lot of people think that living for Christ is going to church on Sunday
and, you know, putting that marking that
off is, oh, I'm a Christian and or having Christian
in your bio and your social media is, right?
I live for Christ.
I shared a post from a preacher.
Like, we have dumbed down, living for
Christ, to just the easy things.
Can I tell you something, living for Christ is simple, but it is not easy.
In other words, we know what to do, but that doesn't make it easy to do it.
You understand what I'm saying?
And so right here, we see the challenge of living for Christ.
First off, living for Christ means worship.
If you look at John, uh, four, verse 19 through 24.
Like I said, we're going to be everywhere.
So just kind of, you know, buckle up.
It says, this the woman saith unto him, the woman at the well.
Sir, I perceive that thou art a prophet.
Our fathers worshiped in this mountain, and ye say that in Jerusalem
is the place where men ought to worship.
Jesus saith unto her, woman, believe me, the hour cometh, when
ye shall neither in this mountain, nor yet at Jerusalem, worship the Father,
ye worship, sorry, something just popped up.
Ye worship, ye know not what, we know what we worship.
For salvation is of the Jews, but the hour cometh and now is,
when the true worshiper shall worship the Father in spirit
and truth, for the Father seeketh such
to worship him.
God is a spirit, and they that worship him must worship
him, in spirit, and truth.
Living for Christ means worship.
I need you to understand something.
Worship goes beyond song.
I believe that worship includes songs.
I was worshiping on the way here.
I was just worshiping with you corporately as Mike and Robin led.
That is a big thing, but you know what our culture has said?
Our culture has dumbed down worship to about a 17
minute set list.
And listen, that is a 17 minute set list that is part of our worship.
But if it ends there, we're not truly worshiping the Lord like we should.
Listen, when we live for Christ, our entire life
is offering praise and worship to him.
When we serve, when we when we obey, when we do all
the things that we're supposed to do, we're going to talk about that.
For example, what does that look like?
Well, living for Christ means giving yourself.
Romans 12, verse one, I beseech you, therefore, brethren, by the mercies of
God, that she presents your bodies, a living sacrifice holy,
acceptable unto God, which is your reasonable service.
And be not conformed to this world, but be ye transformed by
the renewing of your mind that ye may prove what is that good and acceptable
and perfect will of God.
Living for Christ means giving yourself.
Not just a Sunday, not just a devotional
time, you know, once a week.
Listen, when we give our lives to Christ, guess what?
Our lives are no longer our own.
We've been bought with a price.
You understand what I'm saying?
So living for Christ means giving yourself, but also with our worship, living for
Christ means giving your means.
We see right here, and it's much more than giving,
but verse Corinthians 16, verse 2 upon the 1st day of the week.
Let every one of you lay by him in store as God hath prospered him,
that there be no gatherings when I come.
Listen, this is not a giving message, and if it was,
you just have to get over it and listen to it.
But can I tell you something?
Generously giving is part of the Christian worship in our life.
Cheerfully generously giving is what God expects from us.
But you know what people do?
We like to categorize things.
Oh, well, I like this part of being a Christian, but I don't like that part of being a Christian.
Oh, well, hey, listen, I'm a back row Baptist preacher.
You best believe it.
door's open.
I'm there, right?
But don't ask me to do nothing.
Don't, don't, don't come.
We have a culture now.
I don't want you calling me.
That's what I get told all the time.
Don't call me.
Hey, can I come to your house and minister?
Nah, nah, we're good.
Listen, ministry goes far beyond what we do here.
Right?
We have to give ourselves and also give our means.
We can't categorize it in such a way that we control.
Listen, when you give your life to Christ, you've lost control.
And guess what?
It's the most beautiful thing in the world.
Because when I control things, guess what I do?
I mess things up.
You understand what I'm saying?
Living for Christ means separation from the world.
2 Corinthians 6.17.
Wherefore come out from among them and be separate, saith the
Lord, and touch not the unclean thing, and I will receive you.
Listen, I understand the vision that God gave Peter like, hey,
what he was telling him is, look, don't worry about Jew and Gentile.
Just preach the gospel, man.
But listen, there's still unclean things that we should stay away from.
It's called sin.
Sin that separates us is unclean.
It's unholy, right?
We ought to separate ourselves, distance ourselves,
abhor that which is evil, and cling to that which is good.
Why?
Because we are to live for Christ.
We are to live in worship of the king.
Remember Christ means separation from the world.
Sometimes that's difficult, though, isn't it?
And it sneaks up on us with a difficulty.
Man, I guarantee we're the Wednesday night crowd, man.
I bet you we have no problem separating from all the big things.
What about the little things that we keep in our hearts?
What about those selfish, lustful ambitions that we have?
What about those little habits that we have?
What about that heart posture and mindset and critical?
All the things that we try to hide so well?
Listen, hey, we gotta understand, we gotta separate from the world.
If it glorifies the world and the flesh more than God, guess what?
The Bible says separate from it.
And also living for Christ means witnessing.
Mark 5, 18 through 20.
And when he was coming to the ship, he had been possessed when the devil prayed
him, that he might be with him.
Howbeit, Jesus suffered him not, but saith unto him, go home to thy friends and tell
them how great things the Lord hath done for thee and hath had compassion on thee.
This is Jesus casting out a devil.
And he departed and began the publishing, the capitalist, how great things Jesus
had done for him, and all men did marvel.
Let me just tell you something.
When God does something great in your life.
Why, how about you tell somebody about it?
We love talking about the bad things.
Man, my homeowners went up.
My property taxes.
We'll talk about that all day.
Man, you seen inflation?
Listen, I saw 419 at 7 Eleven, and I mean, I hit the brain.
Whoa, I need to stop this vehicle.
I can't afford to go any further, you know what I'm saying?
Listen, we'll talk about that all day.
Man, we were at church and the music was just kind of louder.
Well, the music was just too low.
Man, they didn't do as many hymns as I wanted to do or he preached too long.
And I do preach, you know, kind of long, so I understand that.
But he preached too long.
And you know what?
We, we, the person that was supposed to be serving,
they didn't, they didn't show up on time.
Well, you don't know what they've been going through this morning.
Well, we love to talk about the bad things.
We let the witness to people and say, hey, look what I've witnessed.
Look at all this gospip and slander that I can push into the world.
The Bible says we ought to be a witness for Christ.
What that means is God has saved us.
He has done great things for us.
Therefore, we share that with others.
It's the challenge of living for Christ.
So it means worship, giving ourselves, giving our means separating
from the world, and witnessing and sharing the
love of Jesus in the gospel.
But also, we see, uh, number two, not just the challenge of living for Christ,
but a challenge of living like Christ.
John 12.
Uh, 20 through 21, let me make sure I have this right.
John 12, 20 through 21, it says, and there were certain Greeks among them
that came up to worship at the feast.
The same came therefore to Philip, which was a Beseda
and of Galilee and desired him, saying, sir, we would see
Jesus.
Living like Christ means getting a vision of him.
I was listening to a message today on real momentum.
You need to go.
especially if you're a man.
August 17th.
It's not a podcast, it's a sermon.
And I don't even know who was preaching it, but man, it was so good, but he talked
about we need to practice the presence of God.
You say, what do you mean by that?
Because God is omnipresent.
He's everywhere.
We don't get to control that.
No, no, no.
But we can control and practice the fact that wherever we are, whatever
we're doing, we're acknowledging that God is with us.
Guess what that does?
That helps us through temptation.
It's a little bit harder.
It's a little bit harder to see when you know God's right there with you.
But when you don't practice his presence, what happens?
Those temptations come in, you think you're all alone.
You think there's no eyes on you, and you give into that temptation.
Therefore, you neglect that God is with you.
By the way, the Holy Spirit of the living God dwells within us.
We have to practice his presence.
That means being spirit filled, right?
We see these Greeks that were Gentiles, right?
They came and they wanted to worship the feast, and they came to
where they were, and they literally desired, and they told, saying, sir,
we would love to see Jesus.
Guys, would love to see Jesus and everything that we do every day.
That's part of witnessing.
That's part of seeing what he's doing.
It's part of acknowledging his presence in the situation.
No matter the tragedy.
Listen, when we were in that hospital room or
that little four, I don't even know where we were.
But we were there and we got the news that Charlotte had passed away, she had not made it.
Listen, in that instance, the gospel became very important to us.
The fact that Jesus lived and died and rose again.
That, listen, that was important.
I had to intentionally God.
I don't know what to do, but God, I know you're with me.
I know you're here.
As practicing his presence.
We had to have a vision of God.
Right?
Living like Christ means doing what he commands.
The Bible says very clearly.
Jesus said, hey, if you let me, keep my commandments.
Right?
John wrote in 1st John, hey, if you let me keep my commandments and they won't be burdensome to you.
Guys, how often do we sit around and we say, man, I have to.
Right?
And I know the cliche is, don't say you have to, you get to, right?
Like, I tell River all the time.
You don't have to go to a farm school.
You get to go to a farm school.
You see what I'm saying?
That's a little privilege, little brat right there.
But we had the mindset of like, man, I have to do this.
I have to study.
I had to I had to go to church.
I had to love others unconditionally.
I had to learn about God.
You know, I had to I had to lead others to Christ.
We have to do all these things.
That's not the heart posture we should have.
If we if we love Christ and we're living like Christ like we should.
We will obey his commandments and they will not be burdens in the Bible says.
Living like Christ means dying to self.
We see here in, uh, Galatians 220.
I'm crucified with Christ, nevertheless, I live, yet not I, but Christ liveth in me.
And the life which I now live in the flesh, I live by the faith of the Son of
God, who loved me and gave himself.
for me.
Living like Christ means dying to self.
Living like Christ means being filled with the Holy Spirit.
Ephesians 518 and be not drunk with wine, wherein is excess, but
be filled with the Spirit.
What does that look like to be filled with a spirit?
I think that's such a thing that we have we have either A,
so trivolized, or we have neglected so much.
We get so scared of the concept being filled with the Holy Spirit.
Well, I'm not charismatic, or I'm not Pentecostal.
I'm not this, I'm not that.
Well, are you saved?
If you had the Holy Spirit within, I want to be filled with the Spirit.
I want to practice that presence of God within me through the Holy Spirit,
that I'm living out the fruit of the Spirit.
Being filled with the Spirit.
Listen, no one wants to plant a fruit tree and it come to maturity with no fruit.
That's a waste of a tree right there.
Who wants an apple tree and no apples?
Who wants a pear tree with no pears?
Right?
When we are filled with the Holy Spirit,
Guess what's gonna happen?
We're going to produce fruit.
If you don't have any fruit, you're not being filled with the Spirit.
To live like Christ to be filled with the Spirit.
Living like Christ means praying.
Right?
We see in Matthew chapter 7, asking, this shall be given you.
Seek, and you shall find, knock, and it shall be open unto you.
For everyone that asketh receiving, and he that seeketh findeth, and to him that knocketh, shall be opened.
I sent Mike a video the other day.
Um, we were talking about some worship leader who,
uh, they laid hands on her and said, hey, you know, you're
going to do mighty things and stuff, and she became an amazing singer,
musician, and is using that gift for the Lord.
And I think I send you, I don't know, was it, was it, uh, Yes.
Oh, what is her last name?
Oh, I'd have to.
I know, I'd have to look at it.
But anyway, she's it's a big, it's a big gospel family, like Southern gospel
group that Collinsworth.
I think it's Kim Collinsworth maybe or something like that.
I'm not sure you need to look it up, okay?
But she gave testimony.
That's what she said.
She said when I was when I was 3 years old, I think either her
dad or her grandpa was a preacher, okay?
And he he was preaching a revival.
And basically, he he read a he read a verse.
I don't know exactly the verse that she said, but basically, say, ask God and you'll receive.
I don't think it was that one, but it was something in the Old Testament about God talking to a prophet or something.
And she said, all I heard was to ask God and I receive.
As a three-year-old.
She said she went into her room that night.
said, God, give me, was it an ability?
I don't know if she particularly asked to be able to play piano.
Give me a gift is what she asked.
Man, I sent you the video.
Did I watch the video?
My goodness.
I believe it was.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yes.
It was Solomon when he asked, hey, God, give me what I need to lead the people.
Absolutely.
So that was the text, okay?
Again, my brain's mush right now, all right?
But either way, she said, God, give me a gift.
And if at a young age, that she was able to play
piano with no lessons.
Okay?
Now you say, well, that's not a big deal.
Her entire life, okay?
Her, her husband, and all her kids have traveled
the world, leading people in worship.
And part of that has been her gift centered around her gift that
she asked for as a 3 year old, laying
in bed one night, God, just give me a gift I can use for you, God
heard, and she received.
How many things do we not have because we don't ask?
I must think about that.
You say, oh, that's not possible.
Go look it up.
Ms. Collinsworth, I don't know her first name, but she plays how
great thou art on the piano.
Let me just tell you something.
If that piano was standing afterwards, I don't know how, 'cause she was killing it.
Why?
Because she asked, and she received.
So living like Christ means praying.
Do we live a life of communication with the Lord?
Listen, when my kids, if there's one thing that I try to teach them and
show them, it's that no matter what is going on in your life, no
matter if you have a good day or a bad day, you can always come and talk to me.
No matter if you're ashamed of what you just did, no matter if you're happy
about what just happened, no matter if you're scared.
It doesn't matter what's going on, you can always come talk to your daddy.
That's what I tell my girls.
Why?
Because we got to live like Christ means praying.
So the challenge of living for Christ, the challenge of living like Christ, and then we see now,
we're gonna end with this, the challenge of living with Christ.
Living with Christ involves looking for his 2nd coming.
John 14, one through 3.
let not your heart be troubled.
Ye believe in God, believe also in me.
In my father's house of many mansions.
If it were not so, I would have told you.
I go to prepare a place for you.
And if I go and prepare a place for you, I will come again and receive you unto
myself that where I am, there ye may be also.
Remember we were rehearsing.
This is the whole concept we're preparing, we're practicing for heaven.
Remember, to live, to live like Christ is, to practice his
presence, to have a vision of Christ.
You do realize that that rehearsal is going to turn into,
we don't have to practice.
He's going to be right there in front of us.
Face to face.
when our faith becomes sight.
Living with Christ involves looking for his 2nd coming.
Guys, listen, if it wasn't for the promise of a second coming.
I don't know how some of us could go through some of the things that we go through.
Living with Christ involves refusing to live beneath your position.
We said it again.
Galatians 2.20, I'm crucified with Christ.
Nevertheless, I live, yet not I, but Christ live within me.
In a life which I now live in the flesh, I live by the faith of the Son of
God, who loved me and gave himself for me.
Listen, if we're living anything other than for
Christ, like Christ and with Christ,
we're not living a life God has given us.
So we see, again, the scripture, 1st Thessalians chapter
one, verse 7, and to you who are troubled, rest with us.
When the Lord Jesus shall be revealed from heaven with his mighty angels.
In other words, listen, hey, we can rest.
Because we know Jesus is gonna return.
You can be a victorious Christian, but victory begins immediately when Jesus
Christ becomes your savior.
Some of you who have accepted Christ may have grown weak and ineffective and living for him.
Again, we are to live for Christ, like Christ, and with Christ.
So tonight, I wonder, how are we measuring up to that?
Are we are we Christ-like?
Are we focused on the task at hand?
Are we witnessing?
Are we giving ourselves?
Are we giving our means?
Are we living a life of worship?
Are we practicing the presence of God?
Are we looking for his 2nd coming?
Are we staying awake and sober?
Listen, today is near.
I think 2 weeks ago I said something like we're closer than we've ever been to the 2nd coming of Christ.
Guess what?
We are 2 weeks closer than we've ever been to the 2nd coming of Christ today.
Are we ready?
When it has been eyes closed all over this place before we get into our prayer time.